MAINAK CHAKRABORTY

+1-240-408-9107 | mchakrab2@student.touro.edu | LinkedIn | Portfolio

OBJECTIVE

My role as a Graduate assistant intersects with my studies in multimedia UX/UI & interaction design. Leveraging tools like Figma, Adobe Creative Cloud, I contribute to pioneering digital solutions, focusing on user experience and research.

EDUCATION

MS in UX/UI & Interaction Design

New York City, NY

Expected Dec 2024

Touro University, Graduate School of Technology

Bachelor of Mass Media Aug 2019

MMK College of Commerce & Economics

University of Mumbai, India

SKILLS & INTERESTS

- Design Skills: Visual Design, Branding, Wireframing, Prototyping, Usability Research, Empathy maps, Web Design, IOS Design
- Software Skills: Foundational HTML5, CSS/CSS3, jQuery, Flexbox, Bootstrap, Grid, Media queries, Responsive Websites
- Designing Tools: Figma, Sketch, InDesign, Illustrator, Photoshop, Illustrator, Balsamiq, Axure, Adobe Light Room, Camera Raw
- Video Editing: Adobe Premiere Pro, Davinci Resolve, Adobe After Effects (Basic)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Touro University – *Graduate Assistant (Graphics)*

New York City, NY

Jun 2023 - Present

- Conducted user behavior research and usability tests to gather insights and improve user experience of university website.
- Spearheaded website content redesign, reducing bounce rate by 20% and increasing time on site by 30%.
- Implemented SEO strategies, boosting organic traffic by 40%.
- Produced and edited video content, contributing to a 5X increase in engagement.

Ipsos Research – Research Associate Marketing Strategy & Innovation

Mumbai, India

Jan 2022 - Jul 2022

- Conducted market research for Mondelez, identifying target markets and customer behaviors.
- Designed and managed surveys and questionnaires, ensuring high-quality data collection.
- Analyzed research data and created reports with actionable insights, increasing customer loyalty by 10%.
- Coordinated with cross-functional teams to improve efficiency and data accuracy.

Raptreels Productions – *Digital Assistant*

Mumbai, India

Jul 2020 - Nov 2021

Commercial Video Editing & Client Support

- · Worked on commercial video editing for clients and provided technical support to deliver high-quality content.
- Collaborated with freelancers to streamline workflow processes, resulting in a 30% increase in client satisfaction ratings.
- Utilized advanced editing techniques to enhance video quality, leading to a 40% increase in views on clients' social media platforms.

Bzinga (Zee Essel Group) – Product Intern

Mumbai, India

Apr 2020 - Jun 2020

App Development & Process Improvement

- Increased app installations on Android and iOS platforms by implementing targeted marketing strategies, resulting in a 38% decrease in average cost per install (CPI) from \$0.40 to \$0.25.
- Analyzed monthly social media performance data to identify key trends and insights, leading to a 20% increase in (MAU) and (DAU).
- Conducted user research, Competitive analysis and implemented feedback to improve app UX.
- Collaborated with the UX team to implement user feedback gathered from social media channels, resulting in a 15% improvement in user experience metrics year-to-date (YTD).

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

<u>Time Management & Productivity App</u> – Interactive Design for Mobile <u>Ticket Booking App</u> – Interactive Design for the Web Jan 2024 - May 2024

Sep 2023 - Dec 2023

- Conducted comprehensive user research and usability testing to identify and address user pain points.
- Performed competitive analysis and user interviews to inform design decisions and validate feature prioritization.
- Designed high-fidelity wireframes and interactive prototypes, enhancing user experience and task efficiency.
- Analyzed feedback from usability tests, iterating on design solutions to improve user satisfaction and app functionality.

CERTIFICATIONS

• Foundation Of User Experience (UX) by Google

Sep 2021

Create High-Fidelity Designs and Prototypes in Figma by Google